Yeah. Um, just man, I I just want to
start off saying I I love our team. I
mean, I love our people, everybody that
that that works on this like every year.
We're so blessed to be able to do this
and like I can't tell you about the like
the coaches, the scouts, um, medical,
everything that goes into this. And then
you know our guys like working the
phones today and like rookie free agency
and the whole process. It's just um we
have great people and um I'm very I'm
very personally very grateful and want
to say thank you to everybody through
the process. I gave you my phone.
>> Well, it's going off.
>> So yeah, with that
Go ahead.
>> No, it's your time.
>> You came in with four picks, come out of
it with as many players as you did and
the guys you got. How excited are you
with the moves you were able to make to
add to this class?
>> Yeah, fortunately people don't want to
trade with us until like the sixth and
seventh round or fifth and sixth round
or some stuff like that. I don't know
why
um that happened like that this year,
but um no, we were I felt like all the
way through we were targeted. We were
clear. We had a we had a plan and uh
you're always going to have some upsets,
you know, through throughout the
process. We had a couple of those for
sure. Um but, you know, the coaches were
awesome about moving forward after those
upsets and and the scouts and everybody
that was working the phones and what uh
the landscape or the board was looking
like. And uh
yeah, it was just ended up just being a
great process. We added some We added
some guys that like all all the way
through that were like, "Okay, cool."
Like like there's a there's a plan.
There's a vision. Um
there's a like collective feel for um
moving forward with these guys and how
they're going to compete with our with
our team.
>> Can you tell us about the decision to
move up for both Steven or move into the
fifth round for both Stevens? Yeah, it
was too big of a gap and u too much uh
too much talent there and and u both
came on 30 visit and
uh we had you know we had a great it's a
really cool thing with the coaches right
like
the you know just
you nodding like
>> I'm agreeing
>> it's like the yeah like the color
announcer from major league right there
um
>> take over man in the bag
>> no I mean
>> fly ball
>> no it was a
>> c
No, like just the process of coming in
and the coaching and Yeah.
>> How surprised
>> that he was still there in the fifth
round. Is that why you jumped in?
>> It was we just
>> uh Yeah, we were pretty surprised. Um
but
>> when it's the guy lasts that long,
you're like, "Okay, how do we how do we
figure this out?" And you know, we did
we did end up we did have a plan to kind
of play the um
you know the you know compensatory game
if you will and and uh
so we were like all right we have the 12
picks next year. What does it look like?
So yeah and the coaches just we had a
lot of buying from the coaches. They're
really excited about them.
>> Mike two two men. Sorry.
>> No thanks for asking Mike a question.
It's great.
>> Two men. They all seemed like they were
energetic and self assured, but yet they
understood what it's going to take to
compete on a Super Bowl winning team. I
know there's like three things that are
in there, but you just seem to go
through all all new players that you
drafted. Yeah, I think it's just again
speaks to just like the alignment with
our with our people and the things we're
looking for. But, um, you don't have to
be like that, you know, to be to be one
of us and for us want to want you here.
I think it's,
you know, so, but it's cool that it's
worked out that way. And, uh, and we got
great, like I said, uh, I think it was
day one. like we have great competition
on our team and uh we have a lot of
depth and be able to add some extra
pieces later in the draft is going to be
uh really fun to sort that out as the
process kind of unfolds.
>> Mike, you guys triple up at the
quarterback position, two seventh
graders today.
>> What are you excited about with those
two players how they can fit into that
competition?
>> Yeah. Well, there's definitely some
special teams value. Um
>> but like you know,
you can never have too many corners, you
know, and I I don't think I've
been a part of a team that has this many
like drafted corners on their on their
team. And so, uh, going into camp, which
is really exciting. So, it's going to be
a fun competition, man. You know, it's
going to be really cool to see, um, get
these guys in here and get moving and
and see where it goes. So, um, and I
know Jay's really excited, too.
>> Mike, uh, you you guys didn't add an
edge in the draft. Um, uh, really
appreciate you either. talk about some
of the guys you've got on the roster
that maybe you think can uh step into
that role.
>> Yeah. Uh
I mean Jared Ivy's a guy that that's um
that had a great great season last year.
You he wasn't active as many days as he
probably wanted but Jamie Sheriff's
another guy for two years been with us.
Uh Connor Oul
um was up and does a lot of great
things. Miss Anybody?
>> Gaines. We got Gaines.
>> Yeah, Jaylen Gaines is back. Um, so I
mean we're really excited about those
guys and they really worked really hard
last year and I think all of them were
ready to go if need be to go play in a
game. It just that's the way the roster
shook out on a week- toeek basis. Um, so
yeah, we're we're fired up about those
guys and again we're so early in our
like the draft kind of normally hits
first week of phase twoish. We're kind
of week ahead in terms of the process
when the players get here. So, we're
early right now, relatively speaking, in
our process. So, uh you know, we're off
to a great start. We got to keep keep
nailing these days with these guys and
and see see where see where it takes us.
>> And you guys, after Monday, you can sign
free agents without it affecting the
comp pick formula. Uh do you guys
anticipate maybe adding more to the
competition at the edge spot?
>> Yeah, we may.
>> Yep. John, with Oul and Ivy specifically
last year, you've had some crunch points
throughout the year where you had to put
some guys on waiverss like the Anthony
and and Jerick to not do that with with
Ivy and Oul. Does that kind of speak to
what you guys thought about them at the
time to expose them to potentially
similar?
>> Absolutely.
>> Very good preseasons.
to credit to our uh you know our pro
Willie and our pro personnel staff with
like identifying like hey like these are
the players that or these are the teams
are looking for a specific position and
excuse me and uh yeah it was definitely
part of the process
>> with Emanuel Wilson. What would you like
about him? Is there some carryover with
like what Dar
>> Yes. I mean, Jay, this guy is an
outstanding special teams player and uh
Mike reminded me today he's, you know,
he's clocked at like 224, you know,
miles per hour with football pads on.
I'm not sure if you can run like that,
Brady, or not, but yeah, pretty fast.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. But, um, no relation. That's
awesome. But, uh, well played, sir. Um
but uh you know he's I mean it's just
just a ton of speed and uh yeah Jay's we
were really excited to be able to get
Jay spent so much time preparing for the
draft and uh it was so great to be able
to get like like one of his very top
players he's excited about and fits
>> John you've over the years I feel kind
of expanded the amount
>> that you've expanded the amount of
people you had making the draft calls.
Why is that important you kind of share
that much different people?
>> Yeah, it's just a I mean the scouts put
in they're they're away from their
families so much and you know like
Ryan's got two beautiful little kids.
He's gone all the time and they put in
so much time. It's just it's just a cool
thing. They they build these
relationships with these guys and um
it's just great for them to be able to
fin like finally say, "Hey man, we're
going to select you." and uh you know
hand the phone to the head coach and you
know I mean I feel very grateful that
I've been able to do this for a number
of years and you know I hope others in
our in our room will be able to do the
same thing you know be decision makers
and it's just fun to let them let them
do that and you know Bert's it's you
know we're going to be obviously the
team's going to be sold and so is Bert's
last last last draft with us and Becca I
mean she's like this girl works her tail
off and sorry young woman works her tail
off and uh so it was fun for her to be
able we were joking she kind of sounded
a little AIish but you know it was very
fun for her to be able to do that too
and it's just all these back these
people in the background that people
don't you know I get it you guys are
interviewing you know the players and
the coaches and everybody throughout the
year but there's a lot that goes in this
behind uh behind closed doors
>> Fuller in particular was a guy that it
seemed like people thought might go
higher than you
Good point, I think.
>> Yeah. But what do you guys like about
him? What do you guys see in him? It
sounds like he's got a lot of
versatility what he's done.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, it's I think you're
just looking at like an overall really
good football player and uh again going
through the process, meeting with our
coaches. Um
you know, it's it's tricky tricky with
the multiple position thing, but like
the ability to be able to do those
things is exciting. Uh really smart.
Just
>> let's go out a great football player,
you know. He's played on teams, special
teams player as well.
>> He had a great he had a great visit. I
mean, I say that some guys don't have
great visits. You know what I mean? I
feel like I say that to you guys are
like this guy had a great visit and uh
coach
>> coach is excited. Yeah, you guys are
different area of the board.
>> Deon Eastern.
Yeah, our coaches were were very excited
at a you know a gap player that can get
up and down the line of scrimmage and
has some upside as a pass rusher and uh
let's see what Patrick says about him
here. You guys will dig this analytics
talk here. Let's see.
Here's the analytics talk. Uh young
player, solid statline with a better
than average pass rush and a run game
production, good physical profile. These
are the analytics stuff we listen to all
the time. So it's gonna Patrick put this
together for So, I had to give Patrick a
shout out.
>> But no, he's this is this guy's a
monster. I mean, he's huge and like it's
a it's really cool. Again, came in on 30
visit. Coaches were excited. Scouts are
excited. Here we go.
>> Your guys's goal to get young players
who aren't in awe of Super Bowl
champion. Where do you think you
measured up this weekend?
>> Went a good job.
>> Yeah. I mean, they wouldn't have been on
our board really. That's that's a big
that's a huge like uh they weren't going
to be on our board if we felt that way.
>> How did that show?
>> And I say that like the SC like like
that our scouts felt that way, you know.
>> How did that show up in scouting? How
because that's not a game. I guess
sometimes it could be compet
like these guys study these guys
forever. So it's like a you know like
there's we have a competitor scale and
like how they fit in the competitor
scale and what's their self efficacy and
like how are they going to handle um
competition?
>> John John with with Danby um you didn't
didn't have anything at the combine pro
day kind of metric timing wise and
everything. What' you kind of learn
about him from from a number standpoint
through your process? What you could and
what can you kind of tell us about him?
>> Competitive, quick, sticky, and we felt
like, you know, we were missing out on
like not taking in DB from Arizona
because there was like I don't know how
many there was like seven of them taking
that. So,
>> felt like we had to get in the mix. We
had some FOMO there.
>> No, he's he's a very competitive I mean,
they had a great defensive backfield. Um
he came from San Jose State and you know
um yeah everybody's everybody's really
excited about him and he's one of those
guys too you know seventh round you're
getting closer to free agency and it's
like okay who are the guys that are
going to go well so
>> he he told us that um he's run in the
42s and
>> he's a cornerback. He's going to tell
you that. Yeah.
>> But swaggy he's swaggy. Does that
general speed level kind of show up for
you when you when you see him on four
twos or whatever, but like it's there
for you?
>> Yeah, he's fast. Fast. Quick. Yeah.
>> Mike,
>> excuse me.
>> It's been a rough weekend for Mike.
Cold.
>> Mike, a non football one for you. What
do you mean to have your dad here this
weekend when
>> he over there?
>> Where's the old man?
>> Just given his journey from last year.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's awesome. This is uh
shout out all appreciate John for just
the way we the way we operate here. It's
it's uh it's pretty unique. But yeah,
it's been awesome to have him here and
uh see him and him and Bill hang out and
figuring out the draft board and get the
binoculars out and solving the problems
and
>> um play a little golf, you know. Um but
yeah, any anytime we get the chance to
spend time together is definitely chair,
especially where we're at on the map. So
this is really cool.
>> John, I know you're always confident in
the process, but Last year at this time
seemed like there's a lot more
uncertainty just in the playoffs, a lot
of personnel turnover. Seems like this
year
seems to be more of a complete team
going into training going into the
do you feel that way that
>> No, I I liked you mean like right now at
this time after the after the draft I
felt really good about our team. Yeah, I
don't I mean we're I feel I feel really
good about our team. I just have a
natural anxiety that that drives us to
constantly constantly be on the lookout
for how we can improve in every aspect
of our operation or that's
yeah that's basically like
never ever feel like you like it's like
oh yeah we're like you feel good about
your team and you love the guys but
there's a there's a part of our part of
our um philosophy is like what are we
missing you know and and
like like how how do we get better? I
mean, you know, that's just how we roll.
>> Hey, John, we were talking to Josh Graph
and uh Ryan Florence earlier.
>> Oh, cool. Awesome.
>> They've been with you for so long.
>> Yeah.
>> What's the benefit of having guys that
you have that much history with? And
then how do you incorporate new voices
to keep perspectives fresh?
>> Oh, wow. New perspectives. Yeah, that's
great. Um, yeah, there's a there's a
challenge.
So, first of all, the cohesion and being
able to be concise with your uh
communication and like quick, easy, non-
rambling. We don't read reports, you
know what I mean? You can just get at
things really quick. Could solve
problems just in a, you know, just in a
in a quick manner, quicker manner. Um,
on the flip side, the point about like
what are we missing out on is like
there's always this challenge of like,
okay, well, you know, there's a there's
a possibility this player could be this
or, you know, whether it's character,
whether it's, you know, off the- field
stuff or, you know, then on the field
like the play, good and bad. You know,
I've seen the good. We we we basically
try to uh accentuate the positives.
We've seen the player do this. The
easiest thing you can do as an evaluator
is say and the safest thing you can do
for your uh your job's stability is
basically say like guy can't do this and
he can't do that and he can't do that.
Okay. Well then who are you going to
pick? Like somebody's got to play, you
know? So, it's just a constant like, you
know, just inquisitive
challenge uh for these guys all the time
of like knowing at the end of the day
who the player is as much as they
possibly can, but at the end of the day
when we bring them when we bring them in
the building, they still we're still
learning them. You know, there's guys
that have been here three years that
we're still trying to figure out like
not trying to figure out, sorry, trying
to help. on on Stephen. Do you see him
on the right side or the left side or
>> um
No,
>> either side.
>> Thanks.
>> We'll figure all that out later,
>> John. Nice to be able to have the
Lombardi.
>> Oh, yeah. That was fun. Yeah. No, sorry.
I It's been a long weekend. I was like,
Stevens, huh? Sorry. Oh, Bo. Yeah,
sorry. Uh,
yeah, that was fun. Yeah, that was uh I
forget whose idea that was this morning.
It was pretty fun.
>> Anything else?
>> Thank you.
>> Okay, guys.
>> Thanks, y'all.